Scott Greff

Address: 8 – 5 E 10th Ave, Vancouver, BC, V5T 1Y9 Phone: (778) 389-0344 Email: scottiegreff@gmail.com

Repository: <u>github.com/scottiegreff</u>
Portfolio: <u>scottgreff.com</u>

PROFILE

A Full Stack Developer with experience in developing web applications, back-end services, and databases. Proficient in deploying and maintaining applications on cloud-based production environments, designing relational database systems, and integrating third-party services to expand features, speed, and security. Successfully implement data analytics, event-driven microservices, e-commerce platforms, and cross origin admin apps, all while maintaining type-safe, state-managed, and validated codebases.

EDUCATION

- Computer Science Associate Degree, Langara, Vancouver BC
- Audio Engineering, Berkely School of Music, Boston Ma

WORK EXPERIENCE

Full-Stack Developer, Vancouver, BC

2024

Software as a Service (SaaS)

- Developing and maintaining responsive web applications using HTML, CSS, and TypeScript
- Implementing server-side code using Node.js, PHP, and C# for backend development
- Designing database schemas for SQL, ORMs, and NoSQL technologies and optimizing table relationships for efficient queries
- Creating and consuming internal RESTful APIs as well as third-party services and APIs
- Writing clean code by refactoring components, primarily server side rendering, hydrated on client, and using global state management when needed
- Creating asynchronous pipelines for event-driven microservices, such as confirmation emails and SMS reminders
- · Implementing user authentication and authorization using OAuth protocols, ensuring user's credentials and database security
- Establishing and improved CI/CD, JIRA, and Agile Development workflows
- Familiar with AWS cloud services
- Collaborating effectively with senior developers in code reviews and system design planning
- Proficiently utilizing version control systems such as Git and GitHub

Vancouver Public School Board, Vancouver, BC

2007-2019

Secondary High School Tutoring Teacher for Math and Science (2010-2019)

Team Lead of District Program (2014-2019)

- Taught and monitored a classroom of secondary students in various subjects, primarily in Math and Sciences
- Assessed student's knowledge level, broke down complex topics into smaller components to accommodate their learning style
- Participated in ongoing reviews and quality assurance audits to deliver the most effective program processes
- Designed material into milestones and stints, taught effective time management skills, and adjusted stints accordingly
- Advocated for student self-determination, empowerment, inclusivity and diversity

Greff Growler, Vancouver, BC

2016-2019

Partnership, Product Design, Marketing, Sales, Production Lead

- · Designed a range of products including beer growler carriers and home bar accessories
- · Managed the logistics and supply chain coordination for product material, from point of manufacture to retail delivery
- Sold to 15 retail stores and over 20 breweries, selling over 3000 units of main product
- · Launched targeted social media campaigns, conducted A/B testing by using UTMs and Google Analytics
- · Partnered with local community beer festivals to increase product visibility and direct customer engagement

SKILLS & COMPENTENCES

- HTML, CSS
- JavaScript , TypeScript, Java , C++ , SQL , PHP
- NodeJS
- React , Next JS , Express
- PostgreSQL, MongoDB, SQLite
- Mongoose , Prisma , Drizzle
- EC2, IAM, S3, RDS, DynamoBD, EBS, Lambda
- Redux , React Context , Zustand
- Tailwind , Bootstrap
- ShadCN, Radix, Bootstrap, Material-Ul
- React Hook Form , ZOD

- OAuth , Sessions , JWT /JWE , Auth.js , Clerk
- RESTful API
- Git , GitHub,
- CI/CD , Agile Development , Scrum
- Vercel , AWS, Cloudflare, Netlify
- Adobe After Effects , Framer Motion
- Figma, Adobe Illustrator, Adobe Photoshop, Adobe Premiere Pro
- Logic Pro , Cubase , Garage Band , Pro Tools
- Model-View-Controller , Model-View-ViewModel
- Functional Programming, Object-Oriented Programming, Procedural

^{*} REFRENCES UPON REQUEST